# Iva Keranova

Atlanta, Georgia 30324 • 404.384.1637 keranovai@gmail.com • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>keranovai.com</u>

## **UX/UI** Designer

### Multifaceted technical career with a proven track record of innovation and success in visual design.

Dedicated professional UX designer with experience in graphic design, and marketing complemented by a track record of facilitating strong interpersonal relationships between businesses and their users.

## **Professional Experience**

Georgia Expo Manufacturing Corporation – Suwanee, Georgia

## Senior Designer, 03/2017 to Present

Employ a design-thinking approach to ascertain each customer's individualized needs and provide actionable design solutions to meet and exceed those needs. Analyze data derived from surveys, interviews, analytics, and Hotjar, and utilize the findings to significantly improve consumer experience and overall satisfaction. Collaborate with developers through implementation and testing to produce graphics and layouts for use on the web.

#### **Selected Achievement:**

• Spearheaded a redesign for the home page's exhibit backdrop section resulting in a 2% increase in sales and a 14% decrease in visitor bounce rates.

Georgia Expo Manufacturing Corporation-Atlanta, Georgia

### Printed Fabric Marketing Strategist, 03/2017 to 12/2019

Headed the Custom Exhibit Backdrop (CEB) for Georgia Expo Manufacturing, and provided key input and direction on all marketing initiatives. Created and distributed social media advertisements, posts, email blasts, direct mail, catalogs, and other printed collateral to support marketing campaigns. Communicated effectively with clients by conducting thorough consultations to discuss their desired visual needs, and created unique trade show displays that met those needs and precise specifications. Established a comprehensive internal system that approved proofs and tracked orders throughout production processes.

- Designed and implemented internal production systems, still in use today.
- Established a recurring customer base.

Mobile Blobs LLC - Atlanta, Georgia

## **UX/UI Design Contractor, 03/2016 to 03/2017**

Employed an advanced knowledge and understanding of typography, and other design techniques, and delivered clear and attractive graphic designs for numerous mediums. Authored, edited, and distributed communications materials while adhering strictly to all mandatory specifications, even amid stringent deadlines.

## **Selected Achievement:**

• Collaborated with a team of developers to successfully design and implement a user interface for a proprietary project.

Georgia Expo Manufacturing Corporation - Atlanta, Ga

Graphic Designer, 10/2013 to 03/2016

...continued...

# Iva Keranova

Utilized industry-standard tools and processes to conceptualize and create professional quality digital graphics, print graphics, promotional materials, advertisements, and catalogs on behalf of Georgia Expo. Developed and implemented comprehensive email marketing campaigns for both consumer and business-to-business communications. Oversaw quality assurances responsibilities for the printed fabrics department, and ensure strict compliance with all quality standards and expectations.

#### **Selected Achievement:**

• Established social media presence.

Whiter Image - Atlanta, Georgia

#### Graphic Designer, 08/2012 to 09/2013

Developed the design and artistic direction for numerous marketing initiatives from inception to completion, and employed the use of various creative techniques to create concepts that combined effective communication with visual impact. Collaborated with the head of the marketing department to design effective promotional campaigns, advertisements, HTML emails, web banners, brochures, and much more aimed at promoting brand awareness and increasing consumer interest. Managed and maintained four separate WordPress websites, and provided visual and content changes on a daily basis.

#### **Selected Achievement:**

• Cut design time in half by implementing a system of HTML email templates.

# **Educational Background**

UX/UI Design Bootcamp (Expected 2020)

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

Bachelor of Arts in Graphic Design (2016)

Art Institute of Atlanta, Atlanta, Georgia

# **Technical Proficiency**

**Tools:** Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD), GitHub, Git, Figma, Sketch, Sublime Text, InVision, WordPress, Zeplin, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Webflow, Materialize